smc.com 2019-10-08

# Privacy Policy – SMC Networks

##  [Privacy Policy](http://na.smc.com/community/privacypolicy/)

  * February 16, 2017March 5, 2018
  * by [admin](http://na.smc.com/author/admin/ "admin")

## Privacy Policy

This privacy policy governs your use of the software application (“Application”) created by SMC Networks, Inc. (“SMC”).

SMC is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how personal information about you or associated with you is collected, used and disclosed by SMC and its affiliates. By accessing or using the Application, you signify that you have read, understood and agree to SMC’s collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

  1.     1. **Types of Information Collected**

SMC obtains the information you provide when you download and register the Application. When you register with SMC and use the Application, you generally provide information, such as, your name, email address, age, username, password and other registration information.

When you use the Application, SMC may collect certain information automatically, including, but not limited to, the type of device you use, the type of Internet browsers, Application history, Short Message Service (SMS) data, the unique device ID (such as, IMEI number for phones), the IP address of a device, the device data setting, the device operating system, and other software installed on your device, including product keys.

SMC gathers data about the performance of the Application and any errors you may experience. This data helps SMC to diagnose the problems in the Application, to improve the Application and to provide solutions. Error reports can include data such as the type or severity of the problem, details of the software or hardware related to an error, contents of files you were using when an error occurred, and data about other software on your device.

Moreover, the information you provide when you contact SMC help desk are collected, such as data about hardware, software, and other details related to the support incident. Such data includes contact or authentication data, data about the condition of the machine and the application, system and registry data about software installations and hardware configurations, and the content of your chats, SMS and other communications with SMC support,

From time to time, SMC may receive information about you from third parties and other users. SMC may also collect information about you that is publicly available.

  1.     1. **Use of Information**

SMC collects personal information from users in order to better provide you with a personalized, useful and efficient service. SMC uses the information collected to operate, maintain, and provide you the features and functionality of the service, as well as to communicate directly with you, such as to send you email messages and push notifications. SMC may also send you service-related emails or messages (e.g., account verification, change or updates to features of the service, technical and security notices).

**III. Cookie**

SMC uses cookies or similar technologies like single-pixel gifs and web beacons, to record log data. Cookies are small text files sent by SMC to your computer and from your computer or mobile device to SMC each time you visit our website or use the Application. Session-based cookies last only while your browser is open and are automatically deleted when you close your browser. Persistent cookies last until you or your browser deletes them or until they expire.

Some cookies are associated with your account and personal information in order to remember that you are logged in. Other cookies are not tied to your account but are unique and allow SMC to carry out site analytics and customization, among other similar things. If you access the Application through your browser, you can manage your cookie settings but if you disable some or all cookies you may not be able to use the Application. SMC may use third parties like Google Analytics for website analytics. You may opt-out of third party cookies from Google Analytics on its website.  
**III. Third Parties Access to Information**  
Only aggregated, anonymized data is periodically transmitted to external services to help SMC improve the Application and service. SMC will share the information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. SMC may disclose the information that you have provided or that has been automatically collected when:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;
  * when SMC believes in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect its rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
  * with trusted services providers who work on behalf of SMC and who have agreed to adhere to the rules set forth in this privacy statement;

  * SMC is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its asset. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on SMC website <http://na.smc.com/> of any change in ownership as well as any choices you may have regarding this information.

  1. **Opt-Out Rights**

You can stop all collection of information by SMC easily by uninstalling the Application. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. You can also request to opt-out via email, at [**customer.service@smc.com**](mailto:customer.service@smc.com).

  1. **Data Retention Policy, Managing Information**

SMC will retain your data for as long as you use the Application and for a reasonable time thereafter. Also, SMC will retain the information that was automatically collected when you used the Application for up to 24 months, and thereafter may store it in aggregate. If you’d like SMC to delete the information that you have provided to SMC, please contact SMC at [ **customer.service@smc.com**](mailto:customer.service@smc.com) and SMC will respond in a reasonable time. Please note that some or all of the information that you have provided may be required in order for the Application to function properly.

  1. **Children**

SMC does not use the Application to knowingly solicit data from or market to children under the age of 13. In the event that SMC learns that it has inadvertently collected personal information from a child under age 13 without parental consent, SMC will delete that information as quickly as possible. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided SMC with information without their consent, he or she should contact SMC at  ** _customer.service@smc.com_**. SMC will delete such information from its files within a reasonable time.

**VII. Update to Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason. If SMC makes any changes to this Policy, SMC will post the updated Privacy Policy on **_http://na.smc.com/_**. If you object to any changes, you may close your account. Continuing to use the Application after the changes to this Privacy Policy means that you are consenting to the changes. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes.

**VIII. Security**

SMC takes security of your information very seriously and uses commercially reasonable physical, administrative, and technological safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of all information SMC collects and that it shares with service providers. For example, SMC limits access to your information to authorized employees and contractors, who need to know the information in order to operate, develop or improve the Application. However, no security system is impenetrable and SMC cannot guarantee that security of its systems is 100%. In the event that any information under SMC control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, SMC will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations. Please be aware that, although SMC endeavors to provide reasonable security for the information SMC processes and maintains, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches. ** **

  1. **Consent**

** ** By using the Application, you are consenting to SMC processing your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy now and as amended by SMC. “Processing,” means using cookies on a computer/hand held device or using or touching information in any way, including, but not limited to, collecting, storing, deleting, using, combining and disclosing information, all of which may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which SMC or its subsidiaries, affiliates, or service providers maintain facilities. Please note that SMC may transfer information to a country and jurisdiction that do not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which SMC or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities, and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.SMC takes steps to ensure that the data collected under this privacy statement is processed according to the provisions of this statement and the requirements of applicable law wherever the data is located.

  1. **Contact SMC**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [**http://na.smc.com/support**](http://na.smc.com/support) or call **_949-679-8000_** or email **_customer.service@smc.com_**.
